The next two data types are numeric data types.
The first data type, integer, often abbreviated
as int, is a data type that represents whole
numbers, numbers without decimals. In this
112-numbers file, we see a variable we could use
in a game, number_of_tries, and it is set to 3,
which is a whole number. Thus, this variable is
an integer. Sometimes, you may need to verify a
suspected data type, as numbers represented as
strings cannot be used in calculations. I will
add, on line 4, a print statement to print the
type of the number_of_tries variable. The type
function reveals the data type of whatever is in
parentheses after the type function. Thus, I will
type print(type(number_of_tries)) and then select
Run Python File to run this code. In the terminal,
we see that the value is indeed an integer.
Occasionally, you may need to convert a number
that is represented as a string to an integer to
use that number in a calculation. We will see how
to do string-to-number conversions in the topic
on data type conversions elsewhere in this course.